You guys!
여러분!
Whoa! You okay?
와! 괜찮아?
I...
나는...
I just realized how late it is. We should really get going.
이제서야 시간이 얼마나 늦었는지 깨달았습니다. 우리는 정말로 가야 해요.
Did you clog the toilet again?
화장실 또 막았어?
You were gone for a bit.
당신은 잠시 동안 없었습니다.
Want me to...? I could get my mom if you need help.
내가 그러길 원해...? 도움이 필요하면 엄마를 불러올 수도 있어요.
No! I mean, no.
아니요! 내 말은, 아니.
I didn't clog the toilet.
화장실을 막지 않았어요.
It's just we should really get El home.
그냥 엘을 집에 데려가야 할 것 같아요.
Mike, do you really wanna upset Hopper after our close call the other night?
마이크, 정말 호퍼를 화나게 하고 싶은 거야? 어젯밤 우리의 아슬아슬한 통화 후에?
No! The answer is no.
아니요! 대답은 '아니요'입니다.
Now, let's go.
자, 가자.
Wait. But we're still--
기다리다. 하지만 우리는 여전히--
See you tomorrow, Nikki!
내일 봐요, 니키!
Okay, sure. Um...
알았어, 물론이지. 음...
I'm sorry about him. Catch you later.
그 사람에 대해서는 미안해요. 나중에 잡아라.
See ya, Zombie Boy.
또 봐요, 좀비 보이.
Good night, Nikki. And happy birthday.
잘 자요, 니키. 그리고 생일 축하해요.
Oh my god! Oh my god! I'm freaking out!
맙소사! 맙소사! 정말 놀라워요!
Why are you being such a weirdo, dude?
왜 그렇게 이상하게 굴어?
Like, more than usual.
평소보다 더 많이요.
Guys, I know who it is!
얘들아, 나 그 사람 누군지 알아!
Who who is?
누구입니까?
Horde Prime, the big bad who made the Queen, the vines, all of it!
호드 프라임, 큰 나쁜 일 여왕님과 포도나무, 그 모든 것을 누가 만드셨는가!
It's Mrs. Baxter!
백스터 부인이에요!
What?
무엇?
Pinned to my wall
내 벽에 고정
An image of you and of me And we're laughing, we're loving it all
당신과 나의 이미지 그리고 우리는 웃고 있고 모든 것을 사랑하고 있습니다
Oh!
오!
Wow, what's all this?
와, 이게 다 뭐야?
Can't I do something nice for my daughter?
내 딸을 위해 좋은 일을 하면 안 될까요?
Come on, Mom.
어서요, 엄마.
It feels like you're trying to butter me up for something.
노력하고 있는 것 같아요 나한테 뭔가를 주려고.
Okay, fine.
알았어, 알았어.
We're leaving Hawkins!
우리는 호킨스를 떠난다!
Wait, what? What are you... We're moving?
잠깐, 뭐라고요? 뭐야... 우리 이사가는 거야?
Yeah. You were absolutely right. This place isn't for us.
응. 당신은 절대적으로 옳았습니다. 이 곳은 우리를 위한 곳이 아닙니다.
But... No, no. I don't wanna leave.
하지만... 아니, 아니. 나는 떠나고 싶지 않다.
We're due for a new adventure.
우리는 새로운 모험을 떠날 예정입니다.
Sweetie, just a few days ago, you told me--
얘야, 불과 며칠 전에, 당신이 말했잖아요--
Okay, but that was before I had friends here.
좋아, 하지만 그건 그랬어 여기에 친구가 생기기 전에는요.
And what about Dan? We moved here so that you could be with him.
댄은 어떻습니까? 우리는 여기로 이사했어요 그 사람과 함께 있을 수 있도록.
Well, it seems that Daniel and I are on separate paths.
글쎄요 다니엘과 나는 서로 다른 길을 가고 있다는 것을요.
What? You mean you broke up?
무엇? 헤어졌다는 말인가요?
You don't have to concern yourself with that.
걱정하지 않아도 돼요 그것으로.
I already called Aunt Lizzie.
나는 이미 Lizzie 이모에게 전화를 걸었습니다.
She's gonna have the guest room ready for us tomorrow.
그녀가 손님방을 준비할 거에요 내일 우리를 위해.
Tomorrow?
내일?
Yes. Yeah. Uh-huh.
예. 응. 어-허.
But that doesn't mean that we have to leave Hawkins.
하지만 그런 뜻은 아니다 우리는 호킨스를 떠나야 한다고요.
We could find another house, or an apartment, or...
다른 집을 찾을 수도 있고, 아니면 아파트, 아니면...
We can't afford to live here on our own. You know this.
우리는 여기서 혼자 살아갈 여유가 없습니다. 당신은 이것을 알고 있습니다.
Like it or not, it's time for a new experience.
좋든 싫든, 새로운 경험을 할 시간입니다.
And I don't understand why you're so upset.
그리고 난 이해가 안 돼요 왜 그렇게 화났어?
This is what we do.
이것이 우리가 하는 일입니다.
No.
아니요.
It's what you do.
이것이 당신이 하는 일입니다.
I don't know, Dustin. I'm with Will. Just not buying it.
모르겠어요, 더스틴. 나는 윌과 함께 있어요. 그냥 사지 마세요.
You think Mrs. Baxter created those creatures
당신은 생각 백스터 부인이 그 생물을 창조했어요
because of some weird red light?
뭔가 이상한 빨간불 때문에?
Look, I don't have proof, but all signs point to her.
보세요, 증거가 없어요 그러나 모든 징후는 그녀를 가리킨다.
Think about it. She's a scientist who's constantly moving from town to town.
생각해 보세요. 그녀는 과학자예요 끊임없이 도시에서 도시로 이동하는 사람.
She knows all about spores. And ever since she's got here,
그녀는 포자에 대해 모든 것을 알고 있습니다. 그리고 그녀가 여기에 온 이후로,
we've had vines and monsters trying to kill us.
우리는 포도나무를 가졌어 그리고 우리를 죽이려고 하는 괴물들.
But don't you think Nikki would know if her own mom was a mad scientist?
하지만 니키가 알 거라고는 생각하지 않니? 만약 그녀의 엄마가 미친 과학자였다면?
Sometimes adults do bad things.
가끔 어른들이 나쁜 짓을 할 때도 있어요.
Hold on. My dad read an article about some guy in Washington
기다리다. 아빠가 기사를 읽었어 워싱턴에 있는 어떤 남자에 대해
that had a wife and kids who had no clue he was a Russian spy.
그 사람은 아내와 아이가 있었어 그는 그가 러시아 스파이라는 사실을 전혀 몰랐습니다.
So I guess it's not impossible.
그러니 불가능하지는 않다고 봅니다.
So what now? You plan on giving Nikki the bad news?
그럼 이제 어떡하지? 니키에게 나쁜 소식을 전할 생각이야?
You guys too?
당신도요?
Because I got my own bad news.
나 자신에게도 나쁜 소식이 있었기 때문이다.
I just found out my mom is moving us out of Hawkins.
방금 알아냈어 우리 엄마가 우리를 호킨스에서 이사시키실 거야.
Why are you moving?
왜 이사하시나요?
My mom wouldn't tell me exactly.
엄마는 나에게 정확히 말해주지 않았다.
Just that we have until tonight to pack up our stuff and get gone.
오늘 밤까지만 남았어 우리 물건을 싸서 떠나려고요.
Is it because your mom is an evil scientist?
때문인가? 너희 엄마는 사악한 과학자야?
What?
무엇?
Okay, here goes.
좋아, 간다.
Nikki, I think...
니키, 제 생각에는...
your mom created the Queen.
네 엄마가 여왕을 창조하셨어.
Yeah, right. Like my mom's some kind of a deranged psycho
응, 맞아. 우리 엄마처럼 일종의 미친 정신병자같아
obsessed with her research into bringing...
가져오기에 대한 연구에 집착하고 있습니다...
dead... dead plant matter back to life.
죽은... 죽은 식물이 다시 살아납니다.
Oh, crud.
아, 크루드.
Your mom knows she lost control of her creation.
너희 엄마는 알고 계시지 그녀는 자신의 창조물에 대한 통제력을 잃었습니다.
She's trying to skip town.
그녀는 도시를 건너뛰려고 합니다.
No. I mean, that can't be the reason. That's crazy.
아뇨. 그게 이유가 될 수는 없어요. 정말 말도 안 되는 일이군요.
But what if it's not,
하지만 그렇지 않다면
and all Hawkins becomes fertilizer after you leave, including us?
그리고 모든 호킨스는 비료가 됩니다 당신이 떠난 후에 우리도 포함해서요?
Look, I've seen things in the last few days I can't explain,
봐, 난 뭔가를 봤어 지난 며칠 동안 설명할 수 없었어요
a Snow Shark, a Jerk O'Lantern, killer vines.
눈상어, 저크 오랜턴, 킬러 덩굴.
So, do I believe my mom's some kind of a...
그럼 우리 엄마가 일종의...
like a Dr. Frankenstein of plants? No.
마치 식물의 프랑켄슈타인 박사처럼요? 아니요.
But am I 100% certain?
하지만 나는 100% 확신하는가?
I guess not.
나는 아닌 것 같아요.
We can find out for certain
확실히 알아낼 수 있어요
if you can get us into your house without your mom there.
우리를 당신 집으로 데려갈 수 있다면 거기 네 엄마 없이.
She's gotta have evidence of her work.
그녀는 자신의 작업에 대한 증거를 가지고 있어야 합니다.
Dude, are you serious?
친구, 진심이에요?
If we don't find anything, she's in the clear. What do you say?
우리가 아무것도 찾지 못한다면, 그녀는 분명합니다. 당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
Hey, Mom.
안녕, 엄마.
I just... I wanted to say sorry for blowing up at breakfast.
난 그냥... 미안하다고 말하고 싶었어 아침에 폭파해서.
Yeah, well, uh, you know...
예, 음, 어, 아시죠...
Thank you, but I guess we all lose our cool sometimes.
고마워요. 하지만 제 생각에는 우리 모두는 때때로 냉정을 잃습니다.
And you're gonna feel a lot better once we hit the road.
그러면 기분이 훨씬 나아질 거예요 우리가 길을 떠난 후에.
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
어, 응. 응.
Um, also, I was wondering, could we go to the hardware store first?
음, 나도 궁금했는데, 철물점에 먼저 갈 수 있을까요?
I'm not sure I'm gonna find what I need near Aunt Lizzie's.
내가 찾을 수 있을지 모르겠어 Lizzie 이모 댁 근처에 필요한 것.
Sure, we can.
물론이죠. 가능합니다.
But really, we cannot take too long. Got it?
하지만 실제로는 너무 오래 걸릴 수 없습니다. 알았어요?
Rad. Um, can Mike and El come too?
라드. 음, Mike와 El도 올 수 있나요?
Okay, sure. Why not?
알았어, 물론이지. 왜 안 돼?
All units, move, move, move!
모든 유닛, 이동, 이동, 이동!
Go, go, go. Hurry, hurry.
가, 가, 가. 서둘러, 서둘러.
Right where Nikki said it would be.
Nikki가 그렇게 될 것이라고 말한 곳이 바로 그 곳입니다.
Why check the grounds? Last I heard, secret labs are indoors.
근거를 왜 확인하나요? 마지막으로 듣기로는 비밀 연구실이 실내에 있다고 하더군요.
Check it. Last night, I figured out that the X matches that tree.
확인해보세요. 어젯밤에 난 알아냈어 X가 그 트리와 일치한다는 것입니다.
We find the exact angle, we find the Queen.
정확한 각도를 찾아보니, 우리는 여왕을 찾습니다.
All I'm saying is
내가 말하는 건
running over those ugly roses is a community service.
저 못생긴 장미 위로 달려가 커뮤니티 서비스입니다.
Yeah, and all I'm saying is you're an idiot.
응, 그리고 내가 말하는 건 전부야 당신은 바보입니다.
Calling Unit 301.
301호에 전화를 겁니다.
Possible break-in on Elm.
Elm에 침입 가능성이 있습니다.
Copy that. On our way.
복사하세요. 가는 중입니다.
Warmer. Warmer. Burning up.
온열 장치. 온열 장치. 불타오르고 있어.
Ow!
아야!
Boom! Secret lab!
팔! 비밀 연구실!
A secret lab with see-through walls? Great way to hide your secret experiments.
벽이 투명하게 보이는 비밀 연구실이요? 비밀 실험을 숨기는 좋은 방법입니다.
You kidding? A creepy greenhouse is ideal for hiding a secret plant-monster lab.
농담하는 거야? 소름 끼치는 온실이 이상적입니다. 비밀 식물-괴물 연구실을 숨겼기 때문입니다.
But how can we get in?
그런데 어떻게 들어갈 수 있나요?
Obviously not through there.
분명히 거기까지는 아니죠.
Bingo! That's it.
빙고! 그게 다야.
How do you plan on pulling yourself up there?
어떻게 계획하시나요? 거기까지 올라가려고?
Well, I do recall someone winning the Presidential Fitness Test.
글쎄요, 누군가가 이겼던 기억이 나네요 대통령 체력 테스트.
Oh, no.
안 돼.
Nikki, please.
니키, 제발요.
You know that window doesn't work anymore.
그 창문은 더 이상 작동하지 않는다는 걸 아시죠?
So, you are moving?
그럼 이사하는 건가요?
Hawkins is lovely, but I'm afraid that, for us at least, it's a failed experiment,
호킨스는 사랑스럽지만, 그게 두렵습니다. 적어도 우리에게는 실패한 실험입니다.
and we need a new location, somewhere with fresh resources.
새로운 위치가 필요합니다. 신선한 자원이 있는 곳.
I'm sorry to hear that.
그 말을 들으니 안타깝습니다.
No, no sorries necessary.
아니요, 죄송할 필요는 없습니다.
Failure is a vital part of the scientific method.
실패는 중요한 부분이다 과학적 방법의.
It gives us the information we need to adjust for our next experiment.
우리에게 필요한 정보를 제공합니다. 다음 실험을 위해 조정합니다.
What if my experiment is still running? Would you even care?
내 실험이 아직 실행 중이면 어떻게 되나요? 신경이라도 쓰시겠어요?
Listen to me. This move is an exercise in replicability.
내 말을 들어보세요. 이 움직임은 복제 가능성의 연습입니다.
Now, you're gonna be able to repeat this process
이제 당신은 할 수 있을 것이다 이 과정을 반복하려면
and make friends anywhere.
그리고 어디서든 친구를 사귀세요.
This is real life, my life, not some scientific hypothesis.
이게 진짜 인생이야, 내 인생, 어떤 과학적 가설이 아닙니다.
I am aware of that. Why are you acting like I'm such a horrible human being here?
나는 그것을 알고 있습니다. 왜 연기하는 거야? 내가 여기서 그렇게 끔찍한 인간인 것처럼?
Maybe you are.
아마도 당신은 그럴 것입니다.
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
Yes!
예!
How do you know how to do that?
그렇게 하는 방법을 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Some dads teach their kids the art of playing baseball.
어떤 아빠는 아이들을 가르친다. 야구의 예술.
Mine taught me the art of picking a lock.
나는 나에게 자물쇠를 따는 기술을 가르쳐주었다.
Eh, it doesn't look burgled. It's probably just a false alarm.
아, 도난당한 것 같지는 않네요. 아마도 잘못된 경보 일 것입니다.
Yeah, well, houses don't look burgled until they do.
응, 뭐, 집은 도둑맞은 것 같지 않아 그들이 그렇게 할 때까지.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
I'm not finding anything.
나는 아무것도 찾지 못하고 있습니다.
No way Mrs. B will just leave secret research lying around.
말도 안돼 B씨는 그냥 떠날 거야 비밀 조사가 이루어지고 있습니다.
If my stepbrother taught me anything, it's that everything can be a hiding spot.
내 의붓오빠가 나에게 무엇이든 가르쳐준다면, 모든 것이 은신처가 될 수 있다는 것입니다.
Aha!
아하!
Jackpot.
공동 자금.
Hm.
흠.
Well, no sign of forced entry. Let's check the perimeter.
음, 강제 침입 흔적은 없습니다. 둘레를 확인해 봅시다.
That must be Mrs. Baxter.
저 사람은 백스터 부인이 틀림없어요.
That vine.
그 포도나무.
That's from the Upside Down.
거꾸로 된 것입니다.
Oh my god.
맙소사.
That must be how this whole thing got started.
그건 틀림없어 이 모든 일이 어떻게 시작되었는지.
Wait!
기다리다!
Look.
바라보다.
That stuff's, like, hitting a plant with a potion of growth.
그거 마치 식물에 부딪히는 것 같아 성장의 묘약으로.
That thing must really want that goo.
저 놈이 정말 그 끈적끈적한 걸 원하는 게 틀림없어요.
We gotta warn Nikki, Mike, and El right--
Nikki, Mike, El에게 경고해야 합니다. --
Well, no one inside here either.
음, 여기 안에도 아무도 없어요.
Okay then. Let's call in a false alarm and get on out of here.
그럼요. 허위 경보를 울리자 그리고 여기서 나가세요.
Great idea.
좋은 생각이에요.
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Higher! Higher!
더 높은! 더 높은!
That's my head!
그게 내 머리야!
I'm gonna kill you!
난 당신을 죽일 거 야!
Do it later. We're almost there.
나중에 하세요. 거의 다 왔어요.
Got it.
알았어요.
I am not helping you get back down.
나는 당신이 다시 쓰러지는 것을 돕지 않습니다.
Whoa! Whoa!
와! 와!
I'm fine. I'm fine.
잘 지내요. 잘 지내요.
Come on, you stupid...
어서, 멍청아...
Huh? What was that?
뭐? 그게 뭐였지?
How should I know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
나는 간다. 나는 간다.
Dustin and Lucas. They're gonna get caught.
더스틴과 루카스. 그들은 잡힐 것입니다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Dustin!
더스틴!
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Yeah! Never been better!
응! 이보다 더 좋았던 적은 없었습니다!
How are you not dead?
어떻게 안 죽었지?
The grand hobby of gardening broke my fall. Time to snoop.
정원 가꾸기라는 위대한 취미 내 추락을 깨뜨 렸습니다. 스누핑할 시간입니다.
It was probably just a raccoon.
아마 너구리였을 거예요.
In the middle of winter?
한겨울에?
Raccoons gotta eat.
너구리는 먹어야 해.
Hm. What's back there?
흠. 거기 뒤에 무엇이 있습니까?
Hey, you getting hungry?
야, 배고파?
Push!
푸시!
Huh?
뭐?
Is that our car?
그거 우리 차야?
Yes! Chief's gonna kill us!
예! 국장님이 우릴 죽일 거야!
- Why didn't you put the handbrake on? - I did!
- 왜 핸드브레이크를 걸지 않았나요? - 그랬어요!
- I thought I did! - Well, you obviously didn't!
- 그럴 줄 알았는데! - 글쎄요, 당신은 분명히 그렇지 않았습니다!
Aha!
아하!
What do you see here?
여기서 무엇이 보이나요?
A light.
빛.
We have them at home, so does everyone.
우리 집에도 다 있고, 다들 마찬가지예요.
But in a greenhouse,
하지만 온실에서는
where the walls are literally made of glass?
말 그대로 벽이 만들어지는 곳 유리?
Why would you need a light?
왜 빛이 필요할까요?
Because... night?
왜냐면... 밤?
Or it's not all as it seems.
아니면 보이는 것이 전부가 아닙니다.
50% of secret rooms are opened with levers hidden in plain sight.
비밀방의 50%가 열렸습니다. 레버가 눈에 잘 띄지 않게 숨겨져 있습니다.
Watch and learn.
보고 배우십시오.
I said 50%.
나는 50%라고 말했다.
What was all that noise?
그 소음은 다 뭐였지?
Do you know how close you two idiots got to being caught by those cops?
너희 두 바보가 얼마나 가까워졌는지 알아? 그 경찰들에게 잡혀가려고요?
Cops?
경찰?
We saved your bacon. You owe us.
우리는 당신의 베이컨을 구했습니다. 당신은 우리에게 빚을 졌어요.
How'd the cops know we were here?
경찰은 우리가 여기 있는 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
We, uh, may have tripped an alarm.
우리가 경보를 울렸을 수도 있어요.
So we owe you for saving us from the cops you alerted to us?
그래서 우리는 당신에게 우리를 구해준 빚을 지고 있어요 경찰한테서 우리한테 알렸어?
Never mind that now.
지금은 신경쓰지 마세요.
We found this tape showing a plant going nuts for goo that supersizes it.
우리는 식물이 나오는 테이프를 발견했어요 그것을 초대형으로 만든 끈적끈적한 것에 열광합니다.
Wait. Run that back for me again.
기다리다. 다시 한번 실행해 보세요.
Keep up, Lucas. This is perfect. We can definitely use that as evidence.
계속 힘내세요, 루카스. 이것은 완벽합니다. 우리는 그것을 증거로 확실히 사용할 수 있습니다.
That's exactly what we were thinking.
그것이 바로 우리가 생각했던 것입니다.
Holy...
이런...
Ha! In your face! See? 50%!
하아! 당신의 얼굴에! 보다? 50%!
Mike! The H.I.C. has done it again!
마이크! H.I.C. 또 해냈어!
- You okay back there? - Yeah! All good!
- 거기 괜찮아요? - 응! 다 좋아!
Oh my goodness! Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. The wiring in this old car is nuts.
맙소사! 죄송합니다. 죄송합니다. 죄송합니다. 이 낡은 차의 배선은 엉망입니다.
What'd you find? Over.
무엇을 찾았나요? 위에.
Oh, nothing.
아, 아무것도 아니야.
Except, you know, the secret lab!
단, 비밀 연구실만 빼고요!
And that's not all! We know what the Queen is after!
그리고 그게 전부가 아닙니다! 우리는 여왕이 무엇을 쫓고 있는지 알고 있습니다!
Miss Baxter was working on a serum like a miracle Miracle-Gro,
Miss Baxter는 혈청을 작업 중이었습니다. 기적처럼 Miracle-Gro,
this green goo that's strong enough to bring plants back from the dead.
이 녹색 끈적이는 충분히 강해요 식물을 죽음에서 되살리기 위해.
Yeah, we saw a video where it made this plant creature freak out.
응, 우리는 그것이 만들어진 비디오를 봤어 이 식물 생물은 놀라워합니다.
Did you say "green goo"?
"녹색 구"라고 말했나요?
Mike? Mike? Do you copy? Over.
마이크? 마이크? 복사합니까? 위에.
Don't worry. Mike'll be okay. He's got El and Nikki.
괜찮아요. 마이크는 괜찮을 거예요. 그에겐 엘(El)과 니키(Nikki)가 있어요.
This is the lab from the video.
영상에 나온 실험실 입니다.
Whoa.
와.
Dude, is that the Queen?
야, 저 사람이 여왕이야?
It's an exact match!
정확히 일치합니다!
Is everyone okay?
다들 괜찮아요?
- Ugh. Yes. - Yeah. Yeah.
- 어. 예. - 응. 응.
Did we hit something?
우리가 뭔가를 쳤나요?
What was that?
그게 뭐였지?
Oh, no, no, no! Come on! Come on! Come on!
오, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼! 어서 해봐요! 어서 해봐요! 어서 해봐요!
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Guys?
얘들아?
Out, out, out, out, out! Everybody out! Everybody out!
아웃, 아웃, 아웃, 아웃, 아웃! 모두 나가세요! 모두 나가세요!
Nikki! Nikki! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
니키! 니키! 안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼!
How is this happening?
어떻게 이런 일이 일어나고 있나요?
That is physically impossible!
그것은 물리적으로 불가능합니다!
Nikki! Your headphones! It's after your headphones!
니키! 당신의 헤드폰! 그것은 당신의 헤드폰 이후입니다!
What? Why?
무엇? 왜?
The green goo! They're attracted to the green goo!
녹색 끈끈이! 그들은 녹색 점액에 매력을 느낍니다!
Nikki, be careful!
니키, 조심해!
I'm open!
나는 열려있다!
El!
엘자!
Nikki!
니키!
Aw, nuts!
아, 미친!
Mom, start the car!
엄마, 차 시동 좀 걸어주세요!
Okay!
좋아요!
Please, come on! Come on!
제발, 어서! 어서 해봐요!
Nikki, over here!
니키, 여기야!
Run, Wheeler, run!
달려라, 휠러, 달려라!
Come on, please, please, please!
어서, 제발, 제발, 제발!
Here! Throw it here!
여기! 여기에 던져라!
Leave her alone!
그녀를 내버려둬!
Nice save.
좋은 저장입니다.
Hey! Over here!
여기요! 여기요!
Mike! Incoming!
마이크! 들어오는!
El!
엘자!
You saved our lives.
당신은 우리의 생명을 구했습니다.
What were those things?
그 것들은 무엇이었나요?
You know what those were! It was all part of your failed experiment.
그게 뭔지 아세요! 그것은 모두 실패한 실험의 일부였습니다.
You created those creatures and their Queen in your secret lab!
당신은 그 생물을 창조했습니다 그리고 당신의 비밀 연구실에 그들의 여왕이 있습니다!
Wait, what? What? My secret lab?
잠깐, 뭐? 무엇? 내 비밀 연구실?
Yeah. Yeah, and when you realized
응. 응, 그리고 깨달았을 때
your experiment was racking up a body count,
당신의 실험 시체 수를 늘리고 있었어
you decided we should run?
우리가 도망가기로 결정했어?
We should run instead of facing the consequences!
우리는 달려야 해 결과에 직면하는 대신!
Wait, stop! Stop! That's it!
잠깐만요, 그만해요! 멈추다! 그게 다야!
I have no idea where you picked up this wild notion,
나는 전혀 모른다 어디서 이런 터무니없는 개념을 얻었나요?
but I am not responsible for whatever just attacked us.
하지만 난 책임이 없어 방금 우리를 공격한 것이 무엇이든지.
My experiments never made it past the Petri dish, I swear to you.
내 실험은 성공하지 못했어 페트리 접시를 지나서 맹세합니다.
They were nothing but failures.
그들은 실패에 지나지 않았습니다.
It's why I was so astounded
그래서 너무 놀랐어요
that anyone would think they were good enough to steal!
누구나 그렇게 생각하겠지만 도둑질을 할 만큼 훌륭했어요!
"Steal"?
"훔치다"?
But if you didn't create those things,
하지만 당신이 그런 것들을 만들지 않았다면
then who did?
그럼 누가 그랬어?
Mr. Henderson.
헨더슨 씨.
I guess I shouldn't be surprised.
놀라지 않아도 될 것 같아요.
You just can't seem to stay out of trouble.
넌 정말 못 생겼어 문제가 발생하지 않도록.
El!
엘자!